International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers and United Papermakers and Paperworkers Records of Negotiations 5781
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Brotherhood of Pulp Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers and United Papermakers and Paperworkers Records of Negotiations
1942- 1964
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers
United Papermakers and Paperworkers
5781
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
3124624
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 14, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 17, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers, formed in 1909, represented skilled as well as non-skilled workers. It merged with the United Papermakers Paperworkers in 1972, forming the United Paperworkers International Union (UPIU). In 1999, UPIU joined with the Oil, Chemical and Atomic Workers Union to form the Paper, Allied-Industrial, Chemical and Energy Workers International Union (PACE). In 2005, PACE merged with the United Steel Workers of America.
The United Paperworkers International Union was formed in 1972, when the United Papermakers and Paperworkers (1957-1972) merged with the International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers (1909-1972). The United Papermakers and Paperworkers had evolved in 1957 from a merger between the International Brotherhood of Paper Makers (1893-1957) and the United Paperworkers of America (1946-1957).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6046: Archives Union File (AUF) 5955: International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers Files on 1921-1926 Strike
Paper industry workers -- Labor unions -- Sources; International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers; United Papermakers and Paperworkers
3124624
- 1963 Negotiations (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1963 Pensions (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Before 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 45.16 Negotiations (5/64-11/64) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 45.12 1963 Negotiations (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Pacific Coast Association of Pulp and Paper Manufacturers - Uniform Labor Agreement of 1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 45.16.2 Union Proposal (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 45.16.1 Employer Proposal (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 45.20 Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 45.17 NLRB Election and Campaign (Box 1, Folder 10)
- 45.22 Constitution (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 45.24 Councils Conventions (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 45.11 Publications (incl. The Rebel) (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 45.27 Opposition (incl. "The Union Watchman") (Box 1, Folder 14)
- 45.00 Revolt (after 1962 Convention) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- 45.10 West Coast, before 1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)